Alfred H. Barr, Jr. Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - A, 1946, 1952-1955; Abbot, Agnes A. (Wellesley College) Abell, Walter (Michigan State College Franc, Helen M.,Magazine of Art) Alford, Roberta M. (Rhode Island School of Design) Amberg, George (Stolper, T. American Committee for Emigrè Scholars, Writers and Artists Inc.) American Academy of Arts and Science (Jones, Howard Mumford re: The Artist in American Society conference) American Broadcasting Company (Kintner, Robert E.) Ameringen, Lily van (Harper's Bazaar) Aquilera, Mrs. Charles Architectural League of New York (Olindo, Grossi) Architectural Record(Whitbeck, Jeanne) Arensberg, Walter C. Argan, Giulio Carlo Artists Equity Ball (Cecil, James M., Cecil & Presbrey Inc.) Astor, Michael (Rothenstein, John, The Tate Gallery) Australia (Casey, R. G.; Lindsay, Daryl) Austrian, Ray (Ray Austrian & Associates Inc.) Art d'Aujourd'hui(Bloc, Andr) Art Bulletin(Webster, J. Carson, Northwestern University) Art Digest, The (Boswell, Peyton, Jr.) Art News(Frankfurter, Alfred M.) Hess, Thomas B. Seckler, Dorothy) Art News and Review(Denvir, Bernard) Art Quarterly, The Grigaut, Paul L.; Richardson, E. P. Incl. discussion at the meeting of the Consultative Committee of The Art Quarterly, 1953 October 30 File incl: clippings from The New York Times Book Review, 1953 December 20 (Box 1, Folder 1.206 mf 2178:4)
  - American Federation of the Arts, 1952; Cumming, Burton Longwell, Daniel Navas, Elizabeth (incl. ALS) [Neuberger], Roy (Neuberger & Berman) Powers, Wynn Spaeth, Eloise (Box 1, Folder 1.207 mf 2178: [126])
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1952, 1954-1956; Knox, Gordon Kristol, Irving Stein, Sol (incl. broadcast of "Art in the Total State", 1952 December 11) Trilling, Diana File incl. press releases, 1951 March Bulletin, speeches by Ramaswami Aiyer, Max Eastman, Lewis Galantiere, Franco Lombardi, Mary McCarthy, F. S. C. Northrop Harry, N. Rosenfield, Richard H. Rovere, Bertram D. Wolfe, Conway Zirkle, open letter to Picasso and Leger (Box 1, Folder 1.208 mf 2178:146)
  - B, 1953-1955; Baer, Vico Baldwin, Martin (The Art Gallery of Toronto) Baltimore Sun(Trombley, William) Bardi, P. M. Barnes, George (The British Broadcasting Corp.) Barzum, Henri Bayley, John Barrington Becker, Marion R. (Cincinnati Modern Art Society) Bdard, Pierre (Parsons School of Design, incl. ALS) Berenson, Bernard (incl. 2TL) Benson, Gertrude (incl. ALS) Bernstein, Sidney (The Granada Theatres Limited & Transatlantic Pictures Corporation Limited) Block, Mrs. Leigh B. (Mary) Blomquist, Allen Palmer Blumberg, Benjamin Blumberg, Fannie B. (incl. 4 ALS) Bolt, Richard A. Bucarelli, Palma (Galleria Nazionale d'Arte Moderna) Bullard, Mrs. Tower Burke, Caroline (National Broadcasting Company) (Box 1, Folder 1.209 mf 2178:340)
  - Barr - Trip to Europe, 1952; File incl. clippings, AHB handwritten notes, Report on trip to Europe at Trustees Meeting 1952 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 1.210 mf 2178:456)
  - Barr - Sicily, 1953-1954; File incl. clippings, AHB corresp. with Betsy Jones, Marie Alexander, Dorothy Miller, Nathan M. Pusey; Harvard University (Box 1, Folder 1.211 mf 2178:476)
  - Barr - Greensboro [Vt], 1954; File incl. clippings, AHB corresp. with Betsy Jones, Dorothy Miller, Marie Alexander (Box 1, Folder 1.212 mf 2178:502)
  - Barr - Europe TKRR, 1955; File incl. AHB handwritten notes, corresp. with: Dorothy Miller Marie Alexander Burden, William (2 ALS) Brody, Robert (ALS) Martini, Alberto (TLS) Roch, H. P. (ALS) Wickman, E. K. (TLS) (Box 1, Folder 1.213 mf 2178:556)
  - Barr - Birds, [Central Park] Ramble, 1955; Baker, John H. (National Audubon Society) Gulick, Luther Harrison, Richard Edes (incl. press release) Lasker, Loula Markell, Lester (The New York Times Magazine) Merz, Charles (The New York Times) Moore, Mrs. Paul Morrison, Kenneth D. (National Audubon Society) Moses, Robert (Department of Parks, incl. TL AHB-Moses re: other location than Ramble for recreation center) Oaks, John B. (The New York Times) Reid, Ogden R. (The New York Herald Tribune) Riesenfeld, Victor S. Skelton, Kathleen Green Sulzberger, Mrs. Arthur Hays File incl. clippings, 2 maps, press release, letters to The New York Times editor, blueprint of recreation center (Box 1, Folder 1.214 mf 2178:603)
  - Barr-Invitations, 1953-1955; Arnaud, Leopold (Columbia University) Falkenburg, Jinx / McCrary, Tex (National Broadcasting Company, Inc.) Gimbel, Bernard F. Hartwig, Mrs. Arthur R. Sachs, Paul J. (Harvard University) Soby, James Thrall Visson, Vladimir (Wildenstein & Co.) (Box 1, Folder 1.215 mf 2178:737)
  - Barr-Petitions, 1848-1949; Americans for Intellectual Freedom Blake, Peter Brooks, Van Wyck (Committee of One Thousand, "Statement on the Thomas Committee Investigation of Alleged Espionage Activities") Carlson, A. J. Hook, Sidney Kirchwey, Freda Melman, Seymour (incl. letter to editors re: Fascist party headed by Menachem Begin) Pitzele, Bruice Spaeth, Otto Lucien (incl. "Statement on McCarthyism") Ziporkis, Paul File incl. clippings, "Joint Statement on The Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace", 1949 March 25-27, "Statement on the Fighting Group Against Inhumanity" (Box 1, Folder 1.216 mf 2178:761)
  - Burden [William A. M.], 1952-1955; Keck, Sheldon Pedersen, William F. (incl. blueprints of Burden house) Penrose, Roland A. Rich, Daniel Catton (The Art Institute of Chicago) File incl. clippings, TL AHB-Burden re: English collection (Box 1, Folder 1.217 mf 2178:796)
  - C, 1951-1955; Cahill, Holger Carter, John Casey, R. G. (incl. ALS) Catlin, Stanton L. (Tod) Chaloner, Katherine Chanin, Abraham Chaplin, Charles (corresp. re.) Chapman, Gilbert W. Chase, Marion Monks (incl. ALS) Chicago Art Institute (Carl O. Schniewind) Christensen, Sigurd Church, Robert M. (Philbrook Art Center) Citroen, Paul (Senior, John L., Jr.) Clark, L. M. (The Kiskiminetas Spring School, incl. corresp. re: Kiski dormitory) Clifford, Henry (Philadelphia Museum of Art) Clough, Rose Trillo College Art Association of America (Case, James H., Jr., Bard College Danes, Gibson, Ohio State University Faison, Lane S., Jr. incl. The Chicago Review art column by Faison, 1954 November 20 Hope, Henry R. Roob, David M., University of Pennslyvannia Schmeckebier, Laurence Stechow, Wolfgang) Colonial Airlines, Inc. (Cloverdale, Miles,; Dykes, Branch T.) Columbia Broadcasting System (Stanton, Frank, incl. "Facts About Blacklist) Columbia University Press (Jones, David Howell incl. TL Jones-AHB re: manuscript of Myers: The Expressionist Generation) Contini-Bonacossi, Alessandro Cooke, Hereward Lester, Jr. Coolidge, John (Fogg Museum of Art) Cooper, William S. Coward, Thomas R. (Coward-McCann, Inc.) Cutting, Mrs. Charles Suydam Cuttoli, Marie (Box 1, Folder 1.218 mf 2189:889)
  - Catlin [Stanton L.], 1946-1955; Brandt, Joseph (American Institute of Graphic Arts) Blumenthal, Joseph (incl. ALS) Braun book Davis, Richard S. (The Minneapolis Institute of Arts) Harmon, H. G. (Drake University) Herrmann, Erich S. Inverarity, Robert Bruce (International Museum of Folk Art) Klopfer, Donald S. Munn, Russell R. (Akron Art Institute) Munro, Dana G. (Princeton University) Wilson, Thomas J. Woods, Willis F. (Norton Gallery and School of Art) File incl. 8 ALS Catlin, "Modern Mexican Art" by Catlin,American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1950 January 4, revised draft introduction to book, curriculum vitae, introductory remarks by Catlin re: "Design" lecture (Box 1, Folder 1.219 mf 2178:1003)
  - CBS & NBC programs 25th Anniversary Year, 1954; File incl. "Dimension" CBS transcript, 1954 October 16, memoranda (Box 1, Folder 1.220 mf 2178:1155)
  - NBC Televison, 1955; Linkroum, Richard L. Parkhurst, Eleanor Shaw, Elizabeth Ruthman, Robert B. File incl. television script re:What is Modern Painting? by AHB (Box 1, Folder 1.221 mf 2178:1185)
  - Ceremonies: 25th Anniversary Year, 1954; McCray, Porter Sachs, Paul J. (incl. ALS) Wilder, Thornton (corresp. re.) Porter, Allen (incl. 2 memo re: Bulletin) File incl. meeting digest 1954 September 20, list of plans for opening, memo re:Gazette des Beaux Arts special issue on 25th anniversary, press releases, 2 photographs, copy of 1954 MoMA Bulletin (Box 1, Folder 1.222 mf 2178:1219)
  - Circulating Exhibitions, 1950, 1953-1955; Barrie, Erwin S. (Grand Central Art Galleries) McCray, Porter Sabersky, Jane (incl. 2 memos re: 1954-55 and 1955-56 program of the circulating exhibitions) Speyer, Darthea Tannenbaum, Libby (Box 1, Folder 1.223 mf 2178:1291)
  - D, 1952-1955; Dalrymple, Martha (corresp. re.) D'Amico, Victor Daniel, Greta Davidson, Lucia (The City Center of Music and Drama, Inc.) Davis, Curtis Carroll Deknatel, Frederick B. (Harvard University) Delius, F. Dellheim, Peter (Radio Corporation of America) Detroit Institute of Arts, The (Richardson, E. P.) Devree, Howard (The New York Times) DeWald, Ernest (Princeton University) d'Harnoncourt, Ren Dieshl, Gaston (corresp. re.) van Doesburg, Peter Dorasio, Piero (incl. list of requests for illustrations) Dorfles, Angelo Dorner, M/M Alexander Dove, Arthur (corresp. re.) Dover Publications, Inc. (Cirker, Hayward) Downing, Georges E. (Brown University) Downtown Gallery, The (Halpert, Edith Gregor) Dreier, Katherine S. (corresp. re.) Drexler, Arthur Duthuit, Georges Duthuit-Matisse, Marguerite Dyason, Minna (Box 1, Folder 1.224 mf 2178:1316)
  - Dartmouth, 1946, 1951; Ames, Adelbert, Jr. Goodwin, Philip L. Hungerland, Helmut (The American Society for Aesthetics) Moholy-Nagy, L. (Institute of Design) Packard, Artemas Pearson, John Rockefeller, Nelson A. Taylor, Crombie (Institute of Design) File incl. Report to the Exhibitions Committee re: possible exhibition of laboratory demonstrations (Box 1, Folder 1.225 mf 2178:1400)
  - E, 1951-1955; East European fund (Walton, Ann) Eaton, Marjory (corresp. re.) Elliot, James H. Erichsen, von Erffa, Helmut (Rutgers University) Erskine, Peggy Ertel, Herrn K. F. (Box 1, Folder 1.226 mf 2178:1449 mf 2179:4)
  - MoMA Exhibitions (Master List), 1950-1952; Fauve Exhibition (Rewald, John; Wheeler, Monroe ) Modigliani Exhibition (Davis, Bernard, National Philatelic Museum) Picasso Exhibition (Rich, Andrew Catton, The Art Institute of Chicago) Rouault Exhibition (Boumis, Evangelo Brown, May de Hauke, C. M. Soby, James Thrall) (Box 1, Folder 1.227 mf 2178:28)
  - F, 1950-1951; Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors Inc. Ferrari, Oreste Ficke, Gladys B. (Arthur Davison Ficke Foundation) Freeman, Richard B. (University of Alabama) Fund for Intellectual Freedom (Neibuhr, Reinhold) (Box 1, Folder 1.228 mf 2178:49)
  - F, 1955; Fasanelli, James A. Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors (Weston, Harold incl; proposal for Selective Patronage by Foundations and Public-Spirited Individuals) Feldsted, Carol J. (Colorado College) Feroldi, Pietro Ferguson, Marjorie F. Fifth Avenue Coach Company (incl TL AHB-McCarthy re: lawsuit Fine Arts Associates (Gerson, Otto M.) Fischer, Charles Fowler, Harold (5 ALS) Fox, Milton S. (Harry N. Abrams Inc.) Franc, Helen M. Freccia, M/M Vieri Frohman, A.S. File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.229 mf 2178:73)
  - Finkelstein: Conference on science, philosophy & religion - Jewish Theological Seminary, 1953; Cohen, Gerson D. Elisofon, Eliot ("The Ethics and Morals of Creative Expression") Gardiner, Harold C. ( "Morals in Creative Expression") Goodman, Percival ("Creative Expression: The Social Art") Feingold, Jessica (The Insitute for Religous and Social Studies) Kirstein, Lincoln ("Moral Problems in the Preforming Arts") File incl. Conference on Mortal Standings summary statement (Box 1, Folder 1.230 mf 2178:138)
  - G, 1951-1955; Gaff, Ren (incl. 3 ALS, TLS) Gabo, Naum Gallagher, Edward J., Jr. (incl. ALS) Galleria Nazionale d'Arte Moderna (Bucarelli, Palma) Gallup, Donald Gastine, George Gebhard-Gourgaud Foundation (Sincerbeaux) Georges, Alexander (corresp. re.) Giedion, Siegfried Gilbert, Creighton (University of Louisville) Gilkey, Gordon W. (Oregon State College) Gimbel, Bernard F. Girard, An[dr] (2 ALS) Godshaw, Walter F. (incl. ALS Godshaw-AHB re:"Der Sturm") Gold, Alfred Goldwyn, Samuel M. (memo re: portrait commission) Goodman, Percival Goodnough, Robert (inc. curriculum vitae) Goodwin, Philip L. Goodyear, A. Conger Gore, Leroy (The Sauk City Star, incl. clippings) Gourgaud, Baronne Napolon Grand Union Hotel (Shields, Lansing P.) Griffin, William V. Grohmann, William Gropius, Walter Grossblatt, David Guggenheim Museum (Sweeney, James Johnson; Zigrosser, Carl; incl. Guggenheim questionnaire with answers) Guillemin, Bernard (Box 1, Folder 1.231 mf 2178:228)
  - H, 1951-1955; Haag, Hedwig Haas, W. Hahn, Stethan (The Chase National Bank) Hamilton, George Heard (Yale University Hanna, L.C., Jr. Harpers & Brother s (Bessie, Simon Michael) Hartford (Cunningham, C. C., Wadsworth Atheneum) Hartung, Hans Hathaway, C. Heise, Carl Georg Helsing, David Herald Tribune(Heckscher, August) Hillman, Alex L. (Hillman Periodicals) Hildt, Mrs. Thomas Hirshhorn, Joseph H. Hitchcock, Henry-Russell (Smith College Museum of Art) Hochschild, [Mrs. Walter] (corresp. re.) Hodin, Joseph Paul (Institute of Contemporary Arts; incl. curriculum vitae) Holaas, Odd (incl. Tentative Plan for the Establishment of a Scandinavian Art Center in New York City to provide facilities for the exhibition of Applied Arts and Fine Arts) Hook, Sidney (New York University; incl. "Unpragmatic Liberalism" by Hook) Holtzman, Harry (Transformation) Hull, Dorothy K. Haskell, Jean Hess, Thomas B. (Art News, corresp. re:Abstract Painting) Hugnet, Georges (incl. ALS) Hugo, Ian (corresp. re.) Humbler, Robert See (corresp. re.) Hunt, Richard (National Committee for a Free Europe, Inc.) Hunter, Sam (Art Digest, TL Hunter-AHB re: recent attacks on modern art) (Box 1, Folder 1.232 mf 2178:402)
  - Lecture Invitations (Refusals), 1952-1954; Addison Gallery of American Art (Hayes, Bartlett H., Jr.) Allied Arts Association (Owen, Jane Blaffer) Art et Industrie(George, Waldemar) Art Institute of Chicago (Rich Daniel Catton) Baltimore Museum of Art (Breeskin, Adelyn D.) Barnard College (McIntosh, Rustin; Rauch, Basil) Brooklyn Museum (Wijsenbeek, Louis J. F.) Gemeente, Museum (Wijsenbeek, Louis J. F.) J. B. Speed Art Museum (Harris, Paul S.) John Hay Whitney & Co. (Park, Samuel C., Jr.) Los Angeles County Museum (Ross, Marvin C.) Marion Koogler McNay Art Institute (Leeper, Palmer John) Michigan State College (Church, Howard) Minneapolis Institute of Arts (Davis, Richard S.) North Carolina State Art Gallery (Crisp, Lucy Cherry) Northwestern University (Condit W.) Oberlin College (Stechow, Wolfgang) Princeton University (Kennedy, D. R.) San Francisco Museum of Art (McCann Morley, Grace L.) School of the Museum of Fine Arts (Smith, Russell T.) Skidmore, Owings & Merrill (Hartmann, William E.) Smith College Club of New York (Andrade, Eduardo) University of London (Henderson, James) University of Tennessee (Ewing, Kermit C.) Washington University (Hartt, Frederick) Wells College (Rusk, W. S.) Wheaton College (Bush, Lucile E.) Woodrow Wilson Foundation( d'Estournelles, Julie) Yale University Art Gallery (Chase, A. Elizabeth) File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.233 mf 2179:551)
  - International Sculpture Competition [MoMA Exh. #529], 1953-; Butler, Reg (incl. 18 b/w photographs) Grohmann, William Johnson, Theo (Musical America) Kloman, M/M Anthony J. T. Newton, Eric Penrose, Roland Profous, Jaroslav (Federation Internationale Libre des Deportes et Internes de la Resistance) File incl. clippings, press release,Anmerkungen sur Zeit treatise, excerpt from Board of Trustees meeting minutes (Box 1, Folder 1.234 mf 2179:661)
  - International Sculpture Competition [MoMA Exh. #529], 1953; Dudley, Dorothy H. McCray, Porter A. Wrblewski, M. ("Arts and Political Prisoners" essay) File incl.: 3 b/w photographs, clippings, statements, press releases, 1952 October 31 report, excerpt from Henry McBride for Art News, Tate Gallery Essay Minutes of Board of Trustees Meetings: 1953 April 9 1953 March 12 Biographical notes on artists represented in exhibitions circulated in foreign countries: Albert, Calvin Caparn, Rhys Calder, Alexander Esherick, Wharton Harris Ferber, Herbert Gabo, Naum Kelly, Wallace J. Kohn, Gabriel Lippold, Richard Monroe, Keith Roszak, Theodore (Box 1, Folder 1.235 mf 2179:814)
  - International Sculpture Competition (Unknown Political Prisoner) [MoMA Exh. #529], 1953; Artists Equity Assiciation (Newman, Elias; TL Newman-AHB re: method of administering and judging the "Unknown Political Prisoner International Scupture Competition") Butler, Reg Clark, Kenneth Edwards, Joan Freshwater, R. M. (Peter Lubbock Travel Ltd.) Gans, B. d'Harnoncourt, Ren Hendy, Philip (National Gallery of Art) Horgan, Josephine Jebb, Cynthia Kloman, A. J. T. (incl. notes and draft re:) Lawson, Julie Nicholson, Ben Penrose, Roland (TLS Lee Miller) Read, Herbert Rothenstein, John (The Tate Gallery) Webb, John File incl. clippings, list of contestants in American section of competition,Penwith Society Broadsheet, Summer 1953, transcript of radio transmission 1953 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 1.236 mf 2179:984)
  - International Sculpture Competition, ca. 1953-1958; File was not microfilmed (Box 1, Folder 1.236a)
  - International Sculpture Competition Clippings, 1953; File was not microfilmed (Box 1, Folder 1.236b)
  - International Sculpture Competition Photo Album of Prize Winners, 1953; File was not microfilmed (Box 1, Folder 1.236c)
  - London Trip ICA, 1953; John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art Newton, H. H. (ALS) File incl. open letter to Picasso and Leger (Box 1, Folder 1.237 mf 2179:1187)
  - I, 1951-1955; Institute of International Education, Inc. (Holland, Kenneth) Institute for Religious and Social Studies (Bryson, Lyman; incl. program for 1952-1953 Symbolism Seminar) International Graphic Arts Society (Gusten, Theodore J. H.) International Institute for the Conservation of Museum Objects (Pease, Murray; incl. handbook and regulations concerning membership) International Rescue Committee (Cherne, Leo Keppel, Charles T.) Isaacs, Walter F. (University of Washington) Israel (Bartow-Gutmann, Miriam 12 ALS Crowl, Peggy M.; The American Federation of Arts) (Box 1, Folder 1.238 mf 2179:1193)
  - title, 1951-1955; Kantor, Morris Karpel, Bernard (TLS re: bibliography on modern art) Kaufmann, Edgar, Jr. Kayser, Stephen S. (The Jewish Museum) Keck, Sheldon Kende, Herbert A. Kent, Rockwell (Gellert, Hugo) Keppel, Charles T. Kiesler, Frederick J. Kirstein, Lincoln Kopman, Benjamin (incl. ALS) Kornblith, Howard G. Klyne, Maurice Knopf, Mrs. Alfred A. Kootz, Samuel M. (Samuel M. Kootz Gallery) Krasne, Belle Kuhn, Charles L. (Harvard University) File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.239 mf 2179:1260)
  - L, 1951-1955; Labouisse, M/M Henry Lachenal, François (Editions des Trois Collines) Lam, Wifredo (incl. TLS) Lasker, Mrs. Albert D. Lawrence, Jacob (incl. TLS) van Lennep, Eric N. Levitt, Mimi (incl. ALS) Lewin, M/M Albert Lewis, Monty (Coronado School of Fine Arts) Lewyt, Alex M. Lieberman, William S. Life (Thompson, Edward K. Varga, Margrit) Loeb, Julien Lopez-Rey, Jose (New York University) Louchheim, Aline B. (The New York Times) Luce, Henry R. (memo re.) Ludgin, Earle Lynes, Russell (memo re.) (Box 1, Folder 1.240 mf 2179:1329)
  - Lewisohn [Samuel A.], 1944; 1948-1950; 1953; Kootz, Samuel M. File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.241 mf 2179:1387)
  - M, 1952-1955; MacAgy, Douglas Macmillan Company (Scott, Cecil) Maitland-Magill, Robert ManRay, M. Marin, John C., Jr. Marini, Marino Maselli, Titina (incl. 2 ALS) Matalon, Stella Matta (Jouffroy, Alain) Serpan, I. ) Matter, Herbert Maull, Baldwin McCausland, Elizabeth McKelvey, Ralph H. (Florida Artist Group, Inc.) McKim, William L. Meiss, Millard Mellon Institute of Industrial Research (Feller, Robert L.) Mellquist, Jerome de Menil, John (Contemporary Arts Association of Houston, Inc.) Metropolitan Museum of Art (memo re: Slides library, photo and educational services) Miami, University of (McNab, Allan) Middleton, Michael (The Spectator) Milan (Moneta, Nicola) Milwaukee jury (Marquette University mural competition: Herman, David A. Rich, Daniel Catton Zadok, Charles) Miller Company (Tremaine, B. G., Jr.) Miller, Dorothy C.(incl. 5 ALS) Miller, Mitchell H. (incl. ALS) Minguzzi, Luciano Minneapolis Institute of Arts (Davis, Ricard S.) Mitchell, Don L. Mittleman, Mrs. George Mocsanyi, Paul Modigliani (Lejard, A.,Les ditions du Chene) Moe, Henry Allen (John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation) Momentum(Ginzel, Ellen Lanyon Nielsen, Claire L. Waddell, John Henry, incl. ALS Windle, Mary K.) Der Monat(Lasky, Melvin J.) Mongan, Agnes (The Fogg Art Museum) Moore, Mrs. Paul (incl. United Press Red Letter, 1954 November 5-6) Mosse, Eric P. Mudd, Henry T. Myers, Bernard Myers, John (Tibor de Nagy Gallery; incl. 7 ALS) (Box 1, Folder 1.242 mf 2179:1414 mf 2180:4)
  - Magazine of Art, 1952-1953; Franc, Helen M. Goldwater, Robert Phillips, Duncan (The Phillips Gallery) Rudd, Thomas Brown (Munson-Williams-Proctor Institiute) Sachs, Paul J. Soby, James Thrall Somerville, Mrs. L. File incl. notes on proposed Magazine of Art budget 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1.243 mf 2180: [180])
  - N, 1952-1955; Nadelman, Elie Naess and Murphy (Landefeld, Carl) Napoli, Giuseppe (Galleria Pierino) National Counsil of the Arts, Science and Professions Inc. (Fairchild, Henry Pratt) National Gallery of Art (Stites, Raymond S.) Newberry, John S., Jr. (Detroit Institute of Arts) New Century Cyclopedia of Names(Barnhart, Clarence L. ) New Republic The New York Times, The Norton, Mrs., Ralph H. (Greek Earthquake Appeal) Norton Gallery and School File incl. 1 b/w photograph, William Baziotes ALS (Box 1, Folder 1.244 mf 2180:200)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ - General correspondence, 1953-1954; Adams, Philip R. (The Cincinnati Art Museum) Barnes, Roswell P. Dorner, Alexander (Bennington College) Flemming, Arthur S. Halverson, Marvin (incl. proposed agenda for 1954 November 16 meeting) Luce, Henry R. Parkhurst, Charles P. (Oberlin College) Seaver, Esther I. (The Dayton Art Institute) File incl. Minutes of the Division of Christian Life and Work 1953 January 27 1952 December 8-9 with appendices 1952 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 1.245 mf 2180:444)
  - National Council: related articles, examples TKRR, Dinkler, Erica and Erich (Christianity and Art: A Restaurant of Principles) Lane, Bent (Simpson College) Parrish, Ruth K. File incl. printed matter, clippings, 2 b/w photographs (Box 1, Folder 1.246a)
  - Jury: National Gallery of Canada, 1952-1953; (AHB, John Beard, Eero Saarinen jurors) Arthur, Eric (University of Toronto) Bland, John (McGill University) Cram, H. R. Fell, Charles P. Ingram, Eleanor (University of Toronto) Kitchen, J. M. McCurry, H. O. Murry, J. A. (University of Toronto) Saarinen, Eero File incl. competition brochure (Box 1, Folder 1.247 mf 2180:521)
  - New Yorker Profile (Mr. D. MacDonald), 1953; File incl. draft typescript of AHB profile with AHB annotations, answers to questionnaire (Box 1, Folder 1.248 mf 2180:678)
  - O, 1951-1955; Oehley, Leonie (incl. ALS) Orlando, M/M Felipe Orleans, Ilo (Flak & Orleans) Orozco, Jos Clemente (memo re:Zapatistas by Orozco) Osborn, Robert Otto, Celia Outerbridge, Paul Owen, Kenneth D. M/M Ozenfant, Amede (corresp. re.) (Box 1, Folder 1.249 mf 2180:837)
  - Orangerie [exhibition], 1954-1955; Burden, William A. M. d'Harnoncourt, Ren de Mazia, Violette (The Barnes Foundation) McCray, Porter A. (incl. memo McCray-d'Harnoncourt re: special international xhibitions) Soby, James Thrall Speyer, Darthea Taylor, Francis Henry (The Metropolitan Museum of Art) Wight, Frederick S. (University of California) File incl. agenda of 1954 December 10 meeting of selection committee (Box 1, Folder 1.250 mf 2180:864)